To make our first basic flask app, we're going to need to install flask.
So to do that, it's python dash and pip install flask.
And I already have it, but you should see it downloading.
Okay, I'm going to make a new file.
Now I'm going to save it as app.py.
And then the first thing I'm going to need to do is import flask.
So I'm going to say if I'm lowercase flask, which is the package here, import flask, which is the class.
And then I'm going to make a new app object.
I'm going to say the app is equal to the flask class.
I'm going to instantiate it with Thunder Name.
Now the way flask knows how to handle flask is by specifying an app route.
We're going to use something called a decorator to specify this route.
And the way that decorator is work in python is you put them above the function definition.
So I'm going to have a simple hello world method here.
I want it to return hello world.
By in order for flask to know which route to serve this from,
I'm going to have to say use the app symbol.
That's the symbol for decorator and say app.row.
And I'm going to pass an astring here of just a forward slash.
So that's the route for our application.
Now if I save this file, I'm actually, I want to, let me save this file as app.py, as hello.py.
So I can use app.py later.
So I'm going to move this app.py to hello.py.
If you are not sure how to do that from the terminal, you can just do save as and be as code.
Okay.
So to run my flask app, I need to tell flask the flask runner.
What?
Where is my code contained?
I'm going to say it's contained in hello.py.
And then I'm going to save flask runner.
Let me try that again.
So this brings up a local server on our computer.
That's running our application, serving it.
You don't want to use this development server in a production environment.
It doesn't scale.
It's just for testing.
You want to use a production wasky server instead.
So just do not file it.
Something like going to corn would do the trick.
A really great feature of VS code is I can highlight over, I can put my mouse over this link.
And it'll tell me I can command click to follow it.
So if I do that, I should get my hello world flask application here.
Does everyone see the same thing?
Okay.
So that is flask hello world.
It's pretty easy.
Windows folks, you're going to have to try this out for me.
Dollar sign and here, just copy this in here.
It's a comment.
So for Windows folks, try dollar sign and flask app.
Equals and these single quotes, hello.py.
And then this colon and flask run.
Let me know if that works.
Is that a semicolon or a colon after the hello.py?
It's a semi colon.
Thank you.
And I'll just paste it up here.
And I'll say Windows.
That works for me.
Awesome.
Thank you.
Okay.
So save this, command some our handy.
You'll be needing it for the rest of the exercise.
And I will put this at the top right here.
And I'm going to have to open my hello.py.
Here we go.